ebillme.com 2009-11-26

# eBillme Privacy Policy: For Shoppers

**Your Privacy**  
eBillme is committed to keeping your personal information confidential, secure and private. We are not in the business of selling or renting an individual's personal data to other companies for marketing purposes. In this Privacy Policy we provide detailed information on when and why we collect personal information, how we use it, the limited conditions under which we may disclose it to others, and how we keep it secure. 

**What data does eBillme collect?**  
eBillme collects information to facilitate the billing and delivery of eBillme services.   
Personal information that eBillme collects from customers includes the customer's email address.  
Personal information that eBillme collects from merchant partners where you shop includes: 

  * customer's name, email, address and other contact information;
  * historical usage data of eBillme, and 
  * customer subscription records. 

eBillme deems it imperative to collect and use this information. Without it eBillme can not provide you with necessary support and service levels. eBillme does not collect, archive or use any personal financial information.

**How does eBillme use this data?**  
When an individual uses eBillme, the customer is made explicitly aware of the purposes for which eBillme is requesting the personal information. If eBillme identifies other purposes for which the personal information may be used, we will seek the individual's consent prior to such use. eBillme will advise that it is the individual's right to refuse permission for eBillme to use personal information for any new purposes. 

Additional purposes for collecting personal information may be identified to an individual before or at the time of collection. However, at a minimum eBillme will collect personal information for the following purposes: 

  * to establish and maintain effective communication and provide on-going services;
  * to deliver services as subscribed to by the merchants;
  * to deliver services as subscribed to by the consumer;
  * to meet legal, regulatory and settlement requirements; and 
  * to verify the identity of a consumer. 

**How does eBillme collect this information?**   
eBillme collects your information by lawful and fair means using physical or electronic methods. We collect information directly from you when you submit your email address at [www.eBillme.com](http://www.ebillme.com/).

**Supplementation of Information**  
In order to provide order processing services to you, we may on occasion supplement the personal information you submit to us with information from third party sources. 

**ID and Address Verification**  
We use third party software to verify your IP address, billing and shipping information in order to verify your identity.

**LiveChat**  
We provide a livechat feature on our website. This feature is powered by a third party provider; this feature collects your name and email address. This information is used solely to communicate with you regarding your inquiry

**Is my data shared?**  
We use third party web analytics software to track website visits and usage. We do not and will not share, sell, or rent your information to any third party to enable them to market their products and services to you. eBillme may only share your information with third parties with your consent. We maintain the right to release personal information to third parties when we believe it is appropriate to do so to comply with the law and in cases of emergencies. We will also release personal information to cooperate with law enforcement investigations, comply with court orders or subpoenas, to protect our legal rights and the rights of our users, or when we believe it is needed for identity verification and risk reduction. 

**How is my data protected?**  
eBillme takes all reasonable precautions to ensure that your personal information is kept safe from loss, unauthorized access, modification or disclosure. We implement the following safeguards: 

  * Premises security, including badge access to all facilities and iris scanners to the server farm. 
  * Authorized access to digital data, using the latest technological means, including and not limited to firewalls and security software. 

**What Are Cookies?**  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. 

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control these cookies. 

**What email will I receive from eBillme?**

    * **Electronic Bill (eBill):**  
You will receive an eBill when you select eBillme as your method of payment at participating online retailers. You may only opt-out of receiving an eBill by not submitting orders through our merchant partners. The eBill will provide you with instructions to pay for your online order using eBillme as your payment method. 
    * **Newsletters:**  
If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see â€œChoice/Opt-outâ€.
    * **Special Offers and Updates:**  
We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special deals, promotions. You can sign-up on our registration page at [www.eBillme.com](http://www.ebillme.com/). Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you with a way to unsubscribe. Please see â€œChoice/Opt-outâ€. 
    * **Service-related Announcements:**  
We will send you service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, if you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account by sending an email to [[Support@eBillme.com](mailto:Support@eBillme.com) ](mailto:Support@eBillme.com). 
    * Based on the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your user name and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you be email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes. 
    * **Choice/Opt-out:**  
We provide you with the opportunity to â€˜opt-out' of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service, but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference through your eBill.   
If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication, or by emailing us at [[Support@eBillme.com](mailto:Support@eBillme.com) ](mailto:Support@eBillme.com). 

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

**Access to your personally identifiable information**  
If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or deactivate it by making the change on our member information page or by emailing support at [[Support@eBillme.com](mailto:Support@eBillme.com) ](mailto:Support@eBillme.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

eBillme is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the website [www.eBillme.com](http://www.ebillme.com/). Because this website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact [Support@eBillme.com](mailto:Support@eBillme.com) . If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison to resolve your concerns.

**What if I have more questions?**  

For further information regarding our privacy policies or to request information regarding your personal information, you may contact us [[Support@eBillme.com](mailto:Support@eBillme.com) ](mailto:Support@eBillme.com) or by mail at:

MODASolutions  
100-275 Michael Cowpland Drive  
Ottawa, Ontario K2M 2G2

**Links to Other Websites**  

Our website contains links to information on other websites. We do not have any control over these other websites, and therefore we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that you provide while visiting those sites. 

Those sites are not governed by this Privacy Policy, and if you have questions about how a site uses your information, consult that site's privacy statement

If you have any questions or concerns about our collection, use or disclosure of your personal information, please email us at [[Support@eBillme.com](mailto:Support@eBillme.com) ](mailto:Support@eBillme.com).
